Zakaria Abdessamed Brahimit

Django/React Developer & Product Manager

brahimi.zakaria.abdessamed@gmail.com | +213 665915411 **Portfolio:** zakaria-abdessamed-brahimi.me



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

a Full Stack Web Developer with 2 years of Experience specializing in Django & React for creating responsive web applications. Skilled in effectively in gathering and understanding requirements from stakeholders, ensuring clear communication throughout the development lifecycle to achieve project goals.

I'm looking for opportunities on Django/React Developer & Product Manager with an ambitious and growing team that is tackling a major problem.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- ✓ Programming languages: Python, Javascript
- ✓ Frameworks: Django, React, Electronjs
- ✓ Front-end & back-end web development
- ✓ HTML, CSS, Tailwindcss

- ✓ Database Management: PostgreSQL
- ✓ Agile software development
- ✓ Data Structure and Algorithms
- ✓ Source control: Git/GitHub

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sena Research Platform (senaresearch-dz.com)

Fullstack developer & Product Manager | 20 Jan, 2024 - Present

- Leading the development of fullstack application, managing product lifecycle, coordinating with cross-functional teams, and overseeing project milestones.
- Write well-designed and efficient code by using the best software development practices.

Moustachir Agency

Freelance Fullstack developer | December, 2022 - Feb, 2024

- Integrated new functionalities into existing systems, which streamlined operations and improved user interactions.
- Collaborated closely with clients to understand their needs, delivering custom solutions on time and within budget, and facilitating feedback loops for continuous improvement.

Ma Nanny Parisienne

Fullstack Developer | Nov, 2023 - Apr 2024

- Optimized website performance, reducing page load times by 20% through backend improvements and frontend optimizations.
- Developed and integrated APIs for seamless data exchange between frontend and backend systems, enhancing overall application functionality.
- Refactored existing code to improve maintainability and scalability, cutting bug reports by 15% and reducing time spent on maintenance.

The Sparks Foundation

Remote Internship | January, 2022 - March, 2022

- Created and tested applications for several websites.
- Created guides to document the processes of completing the given tasks.

Alpha Center, Batna

Web development Instructor | May, 2021 - March, 2022 | Video Source

- Taught how the internet works and Practiced HTML, CSS, Git, Tailwindcss, and Javascript.
- Covered advanced frontend skills such as flexbox/ grid/ Asynchronous JavaScript/ and a little bit of react is framework.
- built together several web apps such as todo app, URL shortener, landing page, and others.

Student Communities and Clubs

Speaking Sessions & Workshops

- Designed, taught, and evaluated 12 workshops and sessions Presented to groups of over 160 people in student information sessions.
- Taught and mentored in Python, Web development, Agile, and Leadership skills to more than 167 students during Python/Web Bootcamps, and soft skills Courses.

Data Structure & Algo on Leetcode

Problem Solving Skills | Leetcode Profile

Solved 124 Problems on leetcode in different Data structures and algorithms

EDUCATION

University of Batna 2 (Mostefa Ben Boulaïd) | 2018 - 2021

Bachelor of Computer Science - Software Engineering

Higher National School of Management | 2021 - May 2023

Master of Entrepreneurship and Project Management

RELEVANT PROJECTS

Hashnode Clone

- Blogging platform and community of developers that enables you to publish articles developed by Django Rest Framework and Reactjs
- Code Source | Live Review | Original Platform

Medium Clone

- Medium-like web Application using React js and Django Rest Framework
- Code Source | Original Platform

Front end Mentor

- A platform where you can solve real-world HTML, CSS, and JavaScript challenges
- Profile Link

VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE

Google Developers Students Club

Team Leader and Community Founder | Jul 2020 - Aug 2021

- Founded and led the Google Developers Students Club, growing the community from zero to almost 1500 members.
- Organized and hosted 220 tech events, earning a certificate from Google as the most active club in Algeria.
- Facilitated collaborations with industry professionals, providing members with networking opportunities and real-world insights.

TEDx Batna 2 University

Team Lead | Apr 2021 - Jun 2022

- Established and led the TEDx Batna 2 University team
- Coordinated with speakers and volunteers, ensuring smooth event execution and highquality presentations.
- Enhanced community engagement through effective promotion and event management, attracting 1200 attendees.

Teachstars Startup Weekend - Tipaza

Lead Organizer | 03 February, 2022 - May 2022

- a three-day program where aspiring entrepreneurs can experience startup life. In hundreds of cities around the world.
- Organized and executed the Techstars Startup Weekend in Tipaza, overseeing all aspects from planning to execution.
- Built a successful network of local entrepreneurs and investors, fostering future collaborations and startup growth.

CFM - Club des Future Managers

Club President at Higher national School of Management | May, 2022 - May 2023

- Led the Club des Future Managers at the Higher National School of Management, guiding the organization to achieve its strategic goals.
- Organized 34 professional development events and seminars, focusing on leadership and management skills.

Algeria Venture (A-VENTURE)

Ambassador | Nov, 2022 - Jul 2023

- Played a pivotal role in advancing the startup ecosystem in Algeria, contributing to the growth and visibility of innovative ventures.
- Represented A-VENTURE at various national and international events, promoting the initiative's mission and objectives.
- Advocated for and supported the integration of startups into the national economy through strategic partnerships and initiatives.
- Connected startups with resources, mentorship, and funding opportunities by leveraging relationships with key industry players.